[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
as you all know tricentis has released
new version of Tasker
16 on 8th December 2022.
Okay so
I have got a lot of requests from my
subscribers to start
training sessions on Tasker 16. covering
different concepts of automation
so this is our first session where I'm
gonna teach you how can we download and
install the latest version of Tasker
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
so after this session
I'm gonna teach you step by step
how can we
automate the test cases by using
tricentistoska I'm going to cover most
of the basic concepts of present
testoster by using latest version Tasker
16. okay
okay so in this session I'm gonna teach
you how to download and install latest
version Tasker 16. okay so if you see on
the screen there are four steps that you
need to follow first you need to
register with your organization email ID
using the link that is displaying on the
screen so I'm gonna paste these links in
the description so that you can use the
links from the description section okay
and then you have to login
to your support hyphen
hub.resentis.com by using the registered
email ID in the step one
right and then you need to request for a
license using the below link basically
the link that is specified in the third
step okay once you request for the
license the license will be approved by
the corresponding tracing disk manager
so once it is approved you are going to
receive an email
to download and install the Tasker 16
version okay to download and install the
task 16 version you need to use the link
that is specified in the last step okay
I'm gonna paste all these links in the
description okay so now let's jump onto
the system and see how can we perform
all these actions and how can we
download and install present test Tasker
in Windows mission
okay so what is our first step you have
to register with your organization email
ID using link right as I said earlier
so this is the link let me go to the
link uh it's support
hub.trycentish.com okay here you will
find a register
you'll find resistor
link you need to click on register
and then you have to provide all the
fields here okay mister and what is your
name first name last name
and then your mobile number which is
optional and then what is your country
um Street City ZIP
and then language what is your time zone
right and you need to provide your
business address okay so you need to
provide your business address business
email that means organization email so
you cannot provide your personal email
keep this in mind okay and then you need
to confirm your
organization email and provide your
password and confirm the password right
and then click on I agree to the private
policy
and then I'm not a robot right and then
you need to click on submit so as soon
as you register you are going to receive
an email to your organization email ID
okay and then you need to activate
you need to confirm that
the email has been received once that is
done all you need to do is our next step
is you need to log into support
dot com
using the credentials that you have
provided while registering okay so for
me
so I've already logged in here okay if
you see support data and then I am
already logged into my user okay and
then once you log into your
support hyphen
hub.trycentish.com by using your
organization credentials you need to
request for license using below link
okay let me show you that so this is the
link
I'm gonna paste this link in the
description I'm gonna paste all the
links in the description okay you can
access all these links from the
description okay so you need to click on
request cloud training license as soon
as you click on request crowd training
license the request will be sent okay
stating that
deploying this status will be deploying
I already sent this request earlier
that's why it's got deployed and it's
got approved once you are training
license cloud training license been
approved then the state will be changed
to deployed okay
so in my case I've already raised a
request as soon as you raise a request
you will receive an email stating that
the request has been sent to our support
team okay once approved
the status will be changed to deployed
and then you are going to receive an
email stating that
the try centers manager has been
approved your
license and then what you need to do you
need to go to support Hub
tricenters.com third party license let
me show you where what I'm talking about
so you need to go to this link okay I'm
gonna paste this link in the description
okay and then you have to
select trisentis Tasker
under Thai Streisand testoster you can
see Tasker 16 version
right you need to click on
Tasker 16. as soon as you click on
Tasker 16 it's gonna download a DOT exe
file
okay what I already downloaded okay let
me show you what it's going to download
okay so it will download
this particular
yeah so it's gonna download your present
Tasker software
okay so let me show you
how it looks like okay
okay so this is the zip file so it will
be downloading in the form of zip file
okay
so this way
price and is
see tricent is Task are 16 okay
and then you need to extract
60. okay you need to extract the zip
file once you extract
you just need to follow the instructions
you need to click on double click on
this LTS
16 lts.exe file and then see because I
already installed it is asking me to
see I mean either uninstalled repair or
modify because I already installed in
your case you will get a buttons I mean
you will get a
um agreement license agreement you need
to check the check box and then you need
to click on next and follow the
instructions that displays on the screen
it's very very simple self explanatory
okay once you complete your installation
once you complete your installation you
should see a tasker Commander how it's
going to show
so this is the Tasker Commander that you
should see on the menu okay
and you need to click on Tasker
Commander as soon as you click on Tasker
Commander
a commander will be opened if you see
this is my Tasker Commander right and if
You observe about Tasker so I I
clicked on task or Commander one more
time that's why it's showing CFC this is
my latest Tri sentence Tasker 16 version
okay very very latest which is released
on
8th December I think 7th December or 8th
December okay
and if you go to about Tasker so it
shows you the version as
16. once that is done how to
get your license how to basically
activate your license
so the way is you have to click on
Project
right I opened the Tasker click on
Project go to license
and here
because
you are training
license is close cloud-based license you
need to click on connect and then you
have to select connect to Cloud hosted
license server because whenever you
register and request for the cloud
license
for the training
right a license related to Cloud will be
issued for the user okay you need to
select Cloud hosted license in case if
you have a self-hosted license then you
can select this okay in my case it's a
cloud hosted license and then click on
OK and then you need to provide the
credentials that you have given
while registering
when you are registering
to your support try centered support.hub
right so the same email ID and the same
password you have to provide here okay
now
so let me quickly provide
the same email ID and
password that I have
registered with okay as soon as you
click on OK what it will do it's gonna
retrieve your Cloud license okay say
retrieving your Cloud licenses and then
yes you have successfully connected to
the license server and can use Tasker
Commander right away click on OK and
then you can start creating your first
project by using latest Tasker 16
version
okay so in my next session I'm gonna
teach you what are all the
new features and what are all the
different modifications that has been
accommodated in the latest version of
trisentis Tasker 16 version I'm gonna
teach you the advantages what are the
new features added what are all the
features that are got modified right so
all these Concepts I'm gonna explain you
in my next session
after that we are going to start
automating our test cases I'm going to
cover a lot of different concepts
how to automate test cases by using
Tasker latest version 16.
stay tuned
hope you all understand the concepts of
downloading and installing Tasker latest
version 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I upload more
videos thank you
[Music]